<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Online-Presence on Alfred kam </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/online-presence/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Presence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013-05-16-online-presence</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013-05-16-online-presence</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously my co-founder &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/andrewcboos&#34;&gt;Andrew Boos&lt;/a&gt; followed up on the topic of &lt;a href=&#39;http://andrewboos.com/the-difference-between-vcs-and-angels-reboot/&#39;&gt;difference of VCs and Angels&lt;/a&gt;. Continuo on the topic of start ups, this time lets cover online presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your startup&#39;s online presence is relatively important to represent who you are, your cool product and how your customers can benefit from using it. In our startup &lt;a href=&#34;http://appfuel.me&#34;&gt;Appfuel&lt;/a&gt;, it took us a good 2 months to get it straight. Resulting an increase of web traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spilling the beans:&lt;br /&gt;
1. Active social presence in&lt;br /&gt;
- Facebook page&lt;br /&gt;
- Twitter Profile&lt;br /&gt;
- AngelList&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your social presence represents what your startup is made out off. Using these social platforms to pump out messages, cool stories and keep you consumer of interest up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are great tools such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://bufferapp.com&#34;&gt;Buffer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://ifttt.com&#34;&gt;if this then that&lt;/a&gt; to help you manage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Landing Page&lt;br /&gt;
When someone first enters into your site, with average browser size of 1280px  * 720px on desktops and 320px *  480px on mobile. That is some relatively small space, but hey! That will determine if the user will continue reading on. You should spice up the landing page&#39;s image, and it will determine if the reader will continue reading on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. SEO ( Search Engine Optimization)&lt;br /&gt;
Another method to deliver organic traffic to your site are through searches. Make sure you have included meta tags of &#34;description&#34; and &#34;keywords&#34;; A short info in how you can help them; Submit your sitemap into the search engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Blog&lt;br /&gt;
Posting relavent information, tips, stories for the consumer drives relavent traffic and ultimately landing in as your customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tools such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://hittail.com&#34;&gt;hittail&lt;/a&gt; and google analytics to help you drill down to specific keywords that are driving traffic to your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for ours we spiced up our blog a little bit just so the travellers can read the relavent posts, picture below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/assets/img/2013/05/Screen-Shot-2013-05-15-at-8.23.07-PM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-medium wp-image-233&#34; alt=&#34;IAMA - mortal - dev - show all&#34; src=&#34;/assets/img/2013/05/Screen-Shot-2013-05-15-at-8.23.07-PM.png&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;114&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>